

RANKING

RePEc World Last 10 Yrs. ¹	75-th
RePEc World All Yrs. ²	Top 2%
Web of Science h-index ³	28
RePEc-CitEc h-index4	24
SCOPUS h-index ⁵	30
Google Scholar <i>h</i> -index ⁶	41
ResearchGate ⁷ 38.1	5 (Top 1%)

CONTACT

- University of New Haven, 300 Boston Post Rd., West Haven, CT 06516
- 1 +1 (203) 479-4779
- mbalcilar@newhaven.edu
- http://www.mbalcilar.net



- ¹ On 2022-02-25, among 64,009 registered economists. See RePEc IDEAS ID: pba722.
- ² On 2022-02-25, among 64,009 registered economists. See RePEc IDEAS ID: pba722.
- ³ On 2022-02-25, See Web of Science Researcher ID K-7346-2019.
- ⁴ On 2022-02-25, See CitEc Citation Profile ID: pba722.
- ⁵ On 2022-02-25, See SCOPUS Author ID 55921038200.
- ⁶ On 2022-02-25, See Google Scholar ID iNbxXPkAA-AAI&hl.
- On 2022-02-25, See ResearchGate Profile Mehmet Balcilar.

MEHMET BALCILAR

PROFILE

Mehmet Balcilar presently holds the position of Business Analytics Lecturer at the University of New Haven and serves as a research fellow at the Economic Research Forum in Egypt. In addition to his academic roles, he provided advisory and consultancy services to diverse institutions, including the World Bank and the World Health Organization, specializing in data science, risk analysis, statistics, economics, and field surveys. Prior to his current appointments, he held the position of Extraordinary Professor at the University of Pretoria in South Africa and held an affiliation as a Professor at Montpellier Business School in France.

His main research areas include nonlinear time series, forecasting, macroeconomics, central banking, monetary economics, risk management, financial markets, urban & real estate economics, and energy economics.

EDUCATION

PhD	Wayne State University (US)	Economics/Econometrics	1996
MA	Cleveland State University (US)	Applied Economics	1991
MA	Çukurova University (Turkey)	Economics	1990
BA	Dokuz Eylül University (Turkey)	Tourism Management	1986

EXPERIENCE

Education and research: Wayne State University (US, 3 years, 1993-96), University of Pretoria (South Africa, 5 months, 2013-19), Montepellier Business School (France, 1 month, 2018), Kyrgyz-Turkish Manas University (Kyrgyzstan, 3 years, 2001-04), KIMEP University (Kazakhstan, 1 year, 2004-05), Cukurova University (Turkey, 8 years, 1986-90,1996-01, 2005-07), Eastern Mediterrenean University (North Cyprus, 14 year, 2007-Present).

Advisor, consultant, researcher: World Bank (WB), World Health Organization (WHO), OCHA, UNICEF, Procter & Gamble, Standing Committee for Economic and Commercial Cooperation of the Organization of the Islamic Cooperation (COMCEC), Republic of Turkey Nicosia Embassy Development and Cooperation Office (DCO), Republic of Turkey Ministry of Health, Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI), Republic of Turkey Undersecretary of the Prime Ministry, Republic of Turkey Disaster and Emergency Management Authority, Republic of Turkey State Planning Organization, Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey (TUBITAK).

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Publications:

	SCIE and SSCI journals:	175	SC	OPUS journals:	25
	Other peer reviewed journals:	12	Proceedings: Research/project reports:		32
	Book chapters:	5			35
	Conference presentations:	74	Book translations:		3
	Other academic activities:				
	Ph.D. supervision:		27	Master's supervision:	13
Conference and workshop organizations:		17			
Seminar, summer school, and workshops for academicians:					35

Research and publication awards: 13

Research projects and grants: 35

Citations: Web of Science: 3,045 | SCOPUS: 3,562 | RePEc: 2,422 | ResearchGate: 5,224 | Google Scholar: 7,048 (as of 2022-02-25).